ILGWU. Jay Mazur papers, 5780/203
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. Subject files
  - China Committee (AFL-CIO), 1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Notice of organizational meeting, March 7, 1989; letter from Communications Workers of America (CWA) president Morton Bahr to AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland noting that he'd asked Mazur to co-chair the AFL-CIO China Committee with him, and that he'd accepted, September 13, 1989; memos from Michele Briones to Mazur and Susan Cowell re AFL-CIO Committee on China meeting of July 11, 1989; talking points for meeting, July 6, 1989; memo from Mort Bahr re meeting, noting invitation to Tiananmen survivor Liang Heng, June 8, 1989; AFC-CIO News press release, ICFTU Report on Violations of Trade Union Rights in China (May-June 1989); ALF-CIO News press release, "Kirkland Calls for Actions Against China," June 26, 1989; AFL-CIO News press release, "Remarks of Jim Baker, U.S. Workers' Delegate to the ILO Conference," June 26, 1989; AFL-CIO Statement on China by president Lane Kirkland, with cover letter to Mazur and other labor leaders from CWA president Morton Bahr, June 16, 1989; memos between Mazur and Bahr with drafts of statement on Tiananmen Square, "Tragedy in China," October 1989; memos to Mazur from ILGWU international relations director Michele Briones re labor's response to China's human rights abuses, with minutes of August 31 AFL-CIO Committee on China meeting and summary of Lee Cheuk Yan's (Clothing Workers Union of Hong Kong general secretary) visit to the United States; notices of August 31 and November 2 China Committee meeting; AFL-CIO Committee on China Report to the AFL-CIO Executive Council, August 8, 1989; AFL-CIO Committee on China Suggested Speakers, 19 April 1989, with attached newspaper clippings, 1988; newspaper clippings compiled by the AFL-CIO Department of International Affairs re Tiananmen Square and related developments, including report by ICFTU, with cover letter to Mazur, June 30, 1989; "Testimonial to History: Tiananmen Square 1989, April 15 – June 4," photo documentation with captions in English and Chinese, compiled by Hong Kong Alliance in Support of Patriotic and Democratic Movements of China; "Echoes from Tiananmen," Issue No. 1, June 15, 1989, compilation of press reports and original articles, published by Friends of Chinese Minzhu, Hong Kong Trade Union Education Centre, Hong Kong; program for Council on Foreign Relations luncheon, June 13, 1989, featuring Winston Lord, U.S. Ambassador to the People's Republic of China 1985-May 1989, "China and America: Great Walls and Open Doors," with attached handwritten notes by Mazur; Statement on China by Postal, Telegraph and Telephone International, June 8, 1989; Postal, Telegraph and Telephone International Report of IFFTU mission to China, October 16-26, 1988, with newspaper clippings from South China Morning Post, Hong Kong Standard, Asiaweek, Far Eastern Economic Review, Financial Times, 1987-88
  - China, Committee on China (AFL-CIO), Lee Cheuk Yan, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Travel itinerary of U.S. visit of Hong Kong trade unionist Lee Cheuk Yan, August 21, 1989; copies of reimbursement checks; minutes of meeting of Committee on China with Lee Cheuk Yan, August 31, 1989
  - China, Tianamen Square, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    See also China Committee (above) Los Angeles Times Special Report, "The Shattered Dream," re Tiananmen Square repression, June 25, 1989; special report, U.S News & World Report, June 5, 1989; New York Times Magazine, "Human Rights in China," April 16, 1989;" New York Times profile of regime leaders, June 25, 1989; other newspaper clippings
  - China, Workers' Autonomous Federation of China, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    See also China – Han Dongfang "China's Independent Labour Movement," dossier prepared by Hong Kong Trade Union Education Centre and Asia Monitor Resource Center, both in Hong Kong, June 15, 1989; faxed letter to ILGWU international relations director Michele Briones from Hong Kong Trade Union Education Centre expressing concern over establishment of overseas Workers Autonomous Federation of China without consultation with WAF members in exile, December 13, 1990; background description of WAF as it originated in China during and after Tiananmen Square, exiled members, with cover letter from Mazur, May 17, 1990; confidential memo to Mazur from Susan Cowell re overseas WAF preparatory committee, May 16, 1990; memo to Mazur from Briones re stalemate in forming a WAF in exile, July 26, 1990; faxes from Asia Watch with letters from Trini Leung re preparatory committee of WAFOC; IUF News Bulletin, "The Workers' Struggle in China," re Trini Leung, 1989; related correspondence
  - China, Workers' Autonomous Federation of China, 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    See also China – Workers Autonomous Federation of Chin; see also China – Han Dongfang Project description and drafts of booklet of translated excerpts of program broadcasts by WAF in Tiananmen Square between May 24 and June 3, 1989; book proposal, "The Black Hands of Beijing," by Robin Munro and George Black, re human rights abuses, Tiananmen Square, and dissidents Han Dongfang, Wang Juntao, and Chen Ziming; financial records; paper, "Den Xiaoping's Reform and the Chinese Workers' Participation in the Protest Movement of 1989," by Shaoguang Wang, assistant professor of politics, Yale University
  - China, Taiwan, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Letter to Mazur from attorney Jerome M. Garchik re trade with the Republic of China (Taiwan) and alleged murder of Henry Liu, June 9, with attached letter from Garchik to Rep. Robert Matsui; report for Hofstra University Labor Law Journal, "Power in the Eighties: an analysis of the management of pension funds for the attainment of union and public interest goals," by Jerome H. Siegal; report by Asian Center (an independent affiliate of Clergy and Laity Concerned), "'Made in Taiwan': A Human Rights Investigation," by Becky Cantwell, Don Luce, Leonard Weinglass; human rights report from Asia Resource Center and Formosan Association for Human Rights, "Martial Law in Taiwan"; testimony before the House Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs re implementation of the Taiwan Relations Act, including opening statement by Rep. Stephen Solarz, chairman, and statement by David Dean, chairman, American Institute in Taiwan
  - China, Trade (exports), 1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Fact sheet, "Agricultural Exports in the World Market," focused on China, based on U.S. Department of Agriculture publications
  - China, labor (Brandeis), 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Material related to the Brandeis University Program of Labor in China: list of Board of Advisors; notice of board meeting, October 30, 1985; workshop agenda; draft report of trip to China, "A Social Revolution: Labor and Welfare Reform in China," by Leonard J. Hausman; memo from Hausman re trip, June 17, 1985; import growth rate from People's Republic of China from 1983 to 1987; book excerpt, "Trade-Linked Labor Standards," by Ray Marshall, c. 1990
  - Chinatown, 1988-1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    See also ILGWU Local 23-25 "Growth and Development of the Chinatown Garment Industry," by Jay Mazur, n.d.; Garment Industry Development Corporation (GIDC) Chinatown Garment Industry Bulletin re new capital equipment loan program for contractors, in English and Chinese, January 1986, with attached brochures, one in English, one in Chinese, "Help for the Chinatown Garment Industry"; letter to Mazur from the Chinese American Medical Society re managed care, December 20, 1993; memo to Mazur from manager of Local 23-25 Edgar Romney re meeting with Paul Yee, president of CCBA (business association?), outlining talking points, including history of union's involvement with Chinatown, January 17, 1991; letter to Mazur from Romney re decision by Local 23-25 to resign from planning committee for 1989 Chinatown Labor Fair, citing hostility of organizers, June 29, 1989; press release from New York Chinatown History Project re exhibition on Chinese American women in the NYC garment industry, September 8, 1989; "From the Chinatown Press," compilation of English translations of newspaper articles re Graceful Sportswear, Local 23-25, February 1986; New Yorker Reporter at Large article: "Chinatown," June 10, 1991; Women's Wear Daily (1993), Newsday profiles (1990) on Chinatown; booklets, in Korean, describing Union Health Center and history of ILGWU, with cover letter from Mazur to Francisco Chang, Department of Organizing and Field Services, Garment Workers Justice Center, NY, May 18, 1994
  - Chinatown Day Care Center, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    See also Speeches – Child Care (Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown) 1998; see also Speeches – Chinatown Day Care Center 1989; see also Speeches – Chung Pak Day Care Center Opening 1993 Copy of check for $250 contribution to fundraising dinner for Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, with cover letter from president of Cornish Knitgoods Manufacturing Corp., Brooklyn, February 12, 1988; list of contributors and amounts, March 12, 1986; list of locals and contributions to 1984 and 1986 dinners; copy of $2500 check from Liz Claiborne Foundation; copy of check from Biderman Industries for $1240; letter to Mazur from Gov. Cuomo's office declining fundraising dinner invitation to Mrs. Cuomo, January 31, 1986; Wall St. Journal newspaper clipping mentioning local 23-25's prenatal education classes, June 24, 1988; brochure
  - Chinatown Day Care Center, Chung Pak, 1990-1993 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    See also Speeches – Child Care (Garment Industry Day Care Center, Chinatown) 1998; see also Speeches – Chung Pak Day Care Center Opening 1993 Proposal for a Day Care Center in the Chung Pak Project, under construction as a mixed-use facility, also housing a health center and subsidized senior housing, n.d.; remarks by Mazur at press conference kicking off fundraising campaign for day care center, September 26, 1991; outline of background re center; memo from architects re center, March 29, 1991; floorplan; outline for fundraising event, February 25, 1992; fundraising letter from Mazur; January 29, 1992; fundraising flyer in English and Chinese; memo to Mazur from architects re Citibank delay in closing on the mortgage, November 15, 1993; letter to Housing Secretary Henry Cisneros inviting him to opening of center, with cover letter to Mazur, June 1993; memo to Mazur from ILGWU exec vp and manager of Local 23-25 Edgar Romney with attachments re Citibank request that ILGWU guarantee $1.8 million in case of construction cost overruns, March 30, 1990
  - Chinatown Health Clinic, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    See also Speeches – Union Health Center 1998 and 1999; see also Chinatown 1988-1994 Letter to Mazur thanking him for fundraising effort, May 19, 1989
  - Chinatown (Brooklyn), Metropolitan Fashion Center of Greater New York, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    See also Coalition against Anti-Asian Violence 1988 Project proposals: "New Chinese Apparel Marketplace 1989: A New Beginning for the Chinese Apparel Industry," in English and Chinese; "Metropolitan Fashion Center of Greater New York: A Project for the Apparel Industry for the 1990s: A Brief Description – Background and Economic Benefits," June 1989; newsletter of the Garment Industry Development Corporation, GIDC News, with cover story, "GIDC Sets Up Training Program for New Brooklyn Consortium," Winter 1990; flyer for skills training classes by Metropolitan Fashion Center, touting center as worker-friendly; press releases, December 13 and 14, 1990: from GIDC announcing skills training project with Metropolitan Fashion Center; from ILGWU Local 23-25, "Metropolitan Fashion Center to Open, ILGWU Helps Chinatown Garment Industry Expand," in English and Chinese; from Office of the Mayor, in English and Chinese; from Greater Blouse, Skirt & Undergarment Ass'n., Inc., in English and Chinese; from the Continental Garment Manufacturers Ass'n of Greater New York, Inc., in English and Chinese; from Juki America, Inc., "Juki Contributes High Technology to the Metropolitan Fashion Center"; letter from Metropolitan Fashion Center reporting on progress of planning, in English and Chinese, n.d.
  - Citizen Action, 1987-1993 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    See also Speeches – Dubrow, Evelyn 1989 Letter to Mazur from Citizen Action vice president and political director inviting him to dinner honoring ILGWU legislative director Evelyn Dubrow with Lifetime Achievement Award, March 15,1993; invitations and related materials for dinner honoring William Winpisinger, held January 27, 1988; list of quotes by leading public figures about Citizen Action; newsletter, Citizen Action News, year-end 1987; 1986 Election Report, with state-by-state analysis; newspaper clippings
  - City of Hope-Office and Professional Employees International Union (OPEIU) Boycott, 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Letter from Local 30, Office and Professional Employees International Union (OPEIU) describing two-year-old impasse with medical center, fundraising boycott, January 17, 1989; letter from City of Hope CEO giving management's account of situation, October 11, 1988; letter from Mazur to City of Hope CEO, urging resolution of dispute, October 7, 1988; letter to Mazur from City of Hope thanking him for contribution, June 16, 1987; letters to AFL-CIO officials from City of Hope CEO warning that OPEIU's attempt to "interfere" with fundraising efforts by presenting resolution to AFL-CIO to sanction a national boycott would destroy the center's relationship with organized labor, jeopardize jobs, February 2 and 11, 1987
  - Civil Rights, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    Article from the National Journal, March 2, 1991, discussing conflict between blacks (Leadership Conference on Civil Rights), Hispanics (National Council of La Raza), and the AFL-CIO over employer sanctions in hiring illegal immigrants and how the issue was emblematic of divisions in a civil rights movement including minorities beyond African Americans
  - Civil Rights Act of 1990 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Article from Women's Wear Daily discussing bill to put discrimination based on sex, religion, or national origin on the same footin race-based discrimination, quiet opposition by retailers, July 31, 1990
  - Civil Rights Restoration Act of 1988 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    Correspondence from congressmen, Mazur, religious, pro-choice, and pro-life advocates and others favoring or opposing the Danforth amendment, allowing institutions objecting to abortion to receive federal funds
  - Cliffhanger Apparel, 1981-1984 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Complaint filed against Cliffhanger Apparel Company, 265 W. 37th St., New York, for nonpayment of contributions to welfare fund of Local 23-25; notification of award by impartial chairmen, June 14, 1983; audit reports; arbitration award, October 22, 1982; related correspondence
  - Clinton/Gore Campaign, 1992-1995 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Clothe America, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Ad in Women's Wear Daily listing contributors to Clothe America, which raised $3 million in clothing donations for the homeless, March 20, 1990; letter to Mazur from Clothe American chairman Ken Sitomer, CEO of Russ Togs, Inc., thanking him for referral of contributor, April 6, 1990
  - Clothing Bank/J.M. Kaplan Fund, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    Letters to Mazur and ACTWU president Jack Sheinkman from Suzanne Davis, co-chairman of the Clothing Bank/New Clothes for the Homeless, soliciting contributions for program in which manufacturers and retailers donated $4 million in two years in surplus new clothes for distribution to NYC homeless shelters, part of Mayor's Voluntary Action Center; letter from NYC Mayor Ed Koch, thanking Mazur for support, August 18, 1988; letter to Leslie Fay president John Pomerantz, soliciting contribution, noting referral by Mazur, May 19, 1988; list of inventory from manufacturers, December 1987
  - Clothing Manufacturers Association, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    National agreement between CMA and Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, as of May 1, 1995, with cover memo from UNITE general counsel's office
  - Coalition Against Anti-Asian Violence, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Newspaper clipping from Bay News, February 8, 1988, re harassment of Asians in Brooklyn, with cover note to Mazur from Pacific Northwest District Council manager Katie Quan
  - Coalition for Democratic Values, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Letter to AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland from Sen. Howard Metzenbaum seeking contribution to organization promoting liberal, progressive national agenda and counter drift toward right within the Demoratic Party, February 4, 1991
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), 1986-1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Meeting notice of New York City Chapter for December 13, 1993, noting caucus of ILGWU members, memo to Mazur re ILGWU hosting of CLUW National Executive Board meeting of December 16, 1993; letter to Mazur re new CLUW publication re workplace safety, April 24, 1991; draft of letter urging ILGWU members to join CLUW, March 28, 1991; letter to Mazur from president of Cleveland Chapter of CLUW thanking him for his support of the reproductive choice resolution that was submitted to the AFL-CIO Executive Council, July 26, 1990; correspondence between Mazur and CLUW national president re participation in the American Family Celebration, April-August, 1988; conference call for CLUW convention, held November 17, 1988; memo from Mazur to ILGWU regional directors and NYC managers urging that they join CLUW, noting recent decline in ILGWU representation, danger of losing seat on national board, November 17, 1987; memo to Mazur re second annual Working Women's Awareness Week, March 18, 1987; memo from Mazur urging that locals support the NYC chapter of CLUW's International Women's Day event with donation of $50, February 25, 1987, with attached letter from CLUW chapter president describing the event, theme of dependent care; letter to Mazur thanking him for contribution to CLUW Center for Education & Research, January 29, 1987; invoice for reimbursement for travel to CLUW conference, November 24, 1986; invitation to Sol Chaikin to Working Women's Awareness Week, February 10, 1986, with notation by Mazur
  - Code of Conduct (Overseas outsourcing), 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Memo to Mazur calling Sportswear Code of Conduct "totally unenforceable," October 10, 1994; Code of Conduct for Overseas Vendors, with handwritten note; "Signed by Dress Association with ILGWU"; "ILGWU Commitment to Apparel Industry Competitiveness," and description of ILGWU's federal agenda, April 22, 1993; Levi Strauss & Co. Business Partner Terms of Engagement and Guidelines for Country Selection, 1992; Liz Claiborne, Inc., and Its Subsidiaries Standards of Engagement; 1994 Outerwear Negotiations Demands, including code of conduct for overseas vendors, marked "ILG Proposal"; contract agreement re outsourcing, labeled "ACTWU," September 30, 1993; code of conduct by Phillips-Van Heusen: A Shared Commitment: Requirements for Suppliers, Contractors, Business Partners," with cover note to Mazur, August 19, 1992
  - Coelho, Tony, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Letter from Mazur to Majority Whip, Rep. Tony Coelho, expressing regret at his decision to resign from Congress, citing malicious innuendo and diatribe, June 20, 1989; letter to Mazur from Coelho, thanking him for support
  - Commentary (magazine), January, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Copy of magazine
  - Commission on Migration, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    see also Migration Letter to Mazur from the Commission for the Study of International Migration and Cooperative Economic Development confirming his scheduled testimony re Caribbean migration issues at hearing on July 14, 1989; memo to Mazur from ILGWU research director Herman Starobin outlining points for testimony before the commission, June 26, 1989
  - Commission for the Study of International Migration and Cooperative Economic Development, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Testimony by Congressman James Scheuer before the Commission for the Study of International Migration and Cooperative Economic Development, July 14, 1989
  - Committee for National Health Insurance, 1984-1991 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    see also Health Care 1989-1991; see also Health Care – National Coalition on Health Care; see also Health Care – National Leadership Coalition on Health Care Letter from director of Committee for National Health Insurance to Rep. John Conyers praising report by General Accounting Office on Canadian health insurance system, June 24, 1991; memo to committee Board of Directors re Gallup Poll of California residents showing support for national health insurance, May 7, 1990; letters re views of presidential candidates, May-July, 1988; letter re proposed legislation for Medicare catastrophic health insurance, April 9, 1987; statements of UAW and AFL-CIO officials re Medicare catastrophic health insurance before the House Ways and Means Committee, March 10, 1987; minutes of Board of Directors meetings of Committee for National Health Insurance and Health Security Action Council, October 28, 1986 & 87; letter re pain disability claimants under Social Security, improving Medicaid in NY, May 20, 1987; press release from Brooklyn D.A. Elizabeth Holtzman re program for workplace safety, January 27, 1987; letter to ILGWU president Sol Chaikin from Coalition for a National Health System re nonbonding referendum in Massachusetts overwhelmingly supporting national health care, February 13, 1987; press release announcing national conference planned for May 1987; brochure, "America's Babies – Love 'em or Lose 'em," comparing U.S. infant mortality rates with other countries, with cover letter, January 30, 1987; brochure, "Health Care in the United States: An Action Agenda for the 100th Congress," Health Security Action Council and Save Our Security Coalition, with cover letter to newly elected congressmen, January 8, 1987, and letter to Mazur, January 9, 1987; correspondence between committee chair Douglas Fraser and Mazur re appointment to Board of Directors, and press release announcing appointment, October-November 1986; Statement on USHealth Act of 1986 by Douglas A. Fraser, chairman, Health Security Action Council, before the House Select Committee on Aging, September 12, 1986, with cover letter; agenda and material for Board of Directors meeting, October 28, 1986; letter from chairman re effect of tax reform on health and other social benefits, June 11, 1985; requests to Mazur for contributions; report to Mazur on meetings of November 5, 1986, and September 13, 1985; minutes of Board of Directors meetings of Committee for National Health Insurance and Health Security Action Council, February 8, 1984; letters re newspaper articles
  - Communication Workers of America (CWA), 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 10)